Ben Norrichs - Full Stack Developer

https://norrichs.com

About Me

Full-stack developer with experience across a wide variety of knowledge domains. I bring efficiency and deep problem-solving focus. I will quickly understand your team's goals and help you achieve them in any working environment. Let's build something awesome!

Skills and Accomplishments

Project Management skills and Systems Development - integrated time-tracking, budgeting and scheduling and financial review systems in Google Sheets / Google App Scripts platform, integrating Quickbooks data. Effective time management, efficient meeting, communication and decision making skills.

Full stack development - HTML5 / CSS, Javascript / ES6, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, DynamoDB, SQL, RESTfull APIs, ¡Query, React and SvelteJS frameworks, Ruby, AWS (Lambda, API Gateway, S3, etc), Google App Script

Portfolio Projects - https://norrichs.com - Portfolio site (Svelte), Recipe discovery app, (React, consumes external API), Full stack travel app (MERN stack), Full stack H&M ecommerce clone (AWS backend, React frontend, Puppeteer data and assets scraping), Multi-player networked Hearts card game (Mongo / Express backend, Svelte frontend)

Education

Brandeis University - MS Neuroscience 2010 University of California Santa Cruz - BS Biochemistry and Molecular Biology 2002 General Assembly - Software Engineering Intensive 2021

Selected Employment History

Kent Hicks Construction Company West Chesterfield, MA 01084 413-296-0123

Decumanus Green Design Build Lenox, MA 01240

413-281-0046

Westcott G. Clarke **General Contractor** Wilbraham, MA

413-596-2010

Brandeis University Neuroscience Department

Waltham, MA 02453 781-736-3124

UC Berkeley Hellerstein Lab

UC Berkeley, CA 94702 510-642-0646

05/2016 - 02/2021

Role: Foreman, Project Manager, Designer

- Management of field crew and subcontractor activities. Development of project budgets, schedules, and contracts.
- Production of shop drawings, detail drawings, and construction documents facilitating project design and specification, working with clients, architects, and permitting officials.
- Developed business backend systems for time tracking, budgeting and financial review on the Google Sheets platform, including scripting for template functionality and process automation.

07/2013 - 04/2016 **Role: Lead Carpenter**

Carpentry and project management for energy efficient new homes and renovations. Working with plans and coordinating with subcontractors and employees. All phases of construction from foundation to finishes.

04/2012 - 04/2013 **Role: Carpenter**

Carpentry focused on improving energy efficiency. Windows, doors, air-leakage issues. General repair and renovation carpentry.

08/2006 - 12/2009 Role: Graduate student researcher.

Cellular neuroscience research - fruit-fly olfaction and mating behavior. Time-series confocal microscopy of reacting fly brain prep. Animal care and breeding, data analysis. Teaching assistant duties.

05/2003 - 06/2006 Role: Lab Technician and Manager

AIDS, cancer, and nutrition research using stable-isotope labeling of relevant biomarkers. Sample prep, mass-spectrometry data acquisition and analysis. Laboratory management and IT.